He was left for dead. He would not forget.
Man in the Wilderness is a western, adventure, drama
film directed by Richard C. Sarafian.
In the early 1800s, a group of fur trappers and Indian traders are returning with their goods
to civilization and are making a desperate attempt to beat the oncoming winter.
When guide Zachary Bass is injured in a bear attack, they
decide he's a goner and leave him behind to die.
When he recovers instead, he swears revenge on them and tracks
them and their paranoiac expedition leader down.
Zachary Bass, played by Richard Harris.
Captain Filmore Henry, played by John Huston.
Indian Chief, played by Henry Wilcoxon.
Fogarty, played by Percy Herbert.
Grace, played by Prunella Ransome.
Lowrie, played by Dennis Waterman.
Man in the Wilderness is a 1971 American revisionist Western film about a scout for a group of
mountain men who are traversing the Northwestern United States during the 1820s.
Scout Zachary Bass is mauled by a bear and left to die by his companions.
He survives and recuperates sufficiently to track his former
comrades, forcing a confrontation over his abandonment.
The story is loosely based on the life of Hugh Glass.
It stars Richard Harris as Zachary Bass and John
Huston as Captain Filmore Henry.
The expedition in the movie is notable for bringing a
large boat with it, borne on wheels.
The film explores themes of expedition, wilderness, native
american, based on true story, fur trapping.
The tone is emotional.